Chapter 6 Specification Gaming Section 6.1
Introduction Reinforcement learning
the chapter starts with a reminder of some
reinforcement
learning concepts. This includes a quick
dive into the
concept of rewards and reward functions.
This section lays
the groundwork for explaining why reward
design is extremely
important. This section briefly introduces
the concept of Goodhart's
Law. It provides some motivation behind
understanding why rewards
are difficult to specify in a way such
that
they do not collapse in the face of
immense
optimization pressure. Reward
Misspecification With a solid grasp of
the notion of rewards and optimization,
the readers are
introduced to one of the core challenges
of alignment
reward misspecification. This is also
known as the outer
alignment problem. The section begins by
discussing the necessity
of good reward design in addition to
algorithm design.
This is followed by concrete examples of
reward specification
failures such as reward hacking and reward
tampering. Learning
by Imitation this section focuses on some
proposed solutions
to reward misspecification that rely on
learning reward functions
through imitating human behavior. It
examines proposals such as
imitation learning, behavioral cloning,
and inverse reinforcement learning. Each
section also contains an examination of
possible issues and
limitations of these approaches as they
pertain to resolving
reward hacking. Learning by Feedback the
final section investigates
proposals aiming to rectify reward
misspecification by providing feedback
to the machine learning models. The
section also provides
a comprehensive insight into how current
large language models
LLMs are trained. The discussion covers
reward modeling, reinforcement
learning from human feedback,
reinforcement learning from artificial
intelligence
feedback, and the limitations of these
approaches.